九兵衛！
(銀時)新八！
じいさんよ…｡
(敏木斎)大将撃沈
これで終わりじゃ｡
守られて生きてることすら
気づいちゃいねえよ｡
あんちゃん 木刀は？
(雄叫び)
(お妙)帰りたい…｡
あれれ？
どこいっちゃったんだろう｡
ｱﾝﾀの孫は ﾃﾒｴが
いろんな誰かに➡
私… みんなのところへ帰りたい！
♪♪～
(新八)あぁ ようやく見つかった｡
I want to go back...
新八…｡
I...
ﾃﾒｴには よく見えるだろう？
want to go back to everyone.
守り 守られる 大事なﾓﾝがよ！
これで よく見える｡
Shinpachi!
Your captain is finished.
It's over.
Old man.
Your grandchild doesn't seem to realize that...
People have been protecting her, her whole life.
Where's...
your wooden sword?
Uh-oh...
Where could it have gone?
Kyubei?!
Ahh...I finally found them.
Shinpachi.
You can see clearly now, right?
What you're fighting to protect?
What's important?
I can see just fine now!
[It's the final chapter of the Yagyu Arc! The long battle (with a one-episode break) finally comes to a conclusion!]
[Do you remember the rule that whoever breaks the opposing captain's plate wins?]
["A Woman's Best Make Up is Her Smile"]
♪♪～
Tsk, I let my guard down and he got me.
《九兵衛:ﾁｯ…
ｽｷを突かれたとはいえ➡
油断した！》
(雄叫び)
If this fight drags on, the difference in our skill levels will become obvious.
《長期戦になれば
実力差が ﾓﾛに出る！
この勝負 一気にｶﾀを…！》
I have to finish this match right now!
あっ！
♪♪～
《ﾎﾞｸが 新八君を斬るが速いか➡
Will I get Shinpachi-kun first?
Or will you get Grandfather first?
ｷﾐが おじいさまを斬るが速いか》
You think you can beat the lightning speed of my sword?!
《神速を謳われるﾎﾞｸの剣に
挑もうというのか！》
《違う…！ ﾎﾞｸじゃない!!
No!
He's not after me!
彼が狙うのは…
大将を狙い ｽｷができた…》
He's after...
That leaves an opening to go after the captain...!
《危険なのは… ｷﾐだ～っ！》
The most dangerous opponent is...
you!
What?!
《九兵衛:なにっ!?》
Shinpachi!
新八！
はいっ!!
Got it!
You read Kyubei's intentions in the blink of an eye,
《敏木斎:一瞬で
九兵衛の腹を読み➡
その皿を割るだけにとどまらず➡
and not only did you break his plate, but you grabbed both swords as well.
獲物を２本取り戻すとは 見事…》
Outstanding.
But as I told you before-
《だが 言ったはずじゃ…｡
you can't win this battle
この戦い 荷物を抱えて
勝てるほど…➡
carrying a burden like him on your shoulders.
It's not that simple!
甘くはないと！》
Looking after that kid to the very end is what made you lose.
《最後まで あの小僧に
こだわったのが ﾇｼの敗因｡
何をそこまで こだわるの…
うむ!?》
Why were you so determined to do that?!
End it, Shinpachi.
いけ… 新八！
(雄叫び)
♪♪～
Sorry, I lost.
ごめん 負けちった…｡
(近藤)かっ… 勝った～！
We!
Won!
Shinpachi!
(神楽)新八！
ﾍﾍｯ… おわっ！
Don't be so big-headed, dammit!
この… 調子にのんじゃねえぞ
ｺﾗ！
It was mostly thanks to Gin-chan that you won!
ほとんど銀ちゃんの
おかげだろうがぁっ！
That's my brother-in-law for you!
さすがは弟！ 真選組を
任せられるのは ｷﾐだけだ！
You're the only one I can entrust the Shinsengumi to!
誰が弟ですか！
知りませんよ 真選組なんて!!
Who're you calling your bother-in-law?!
I don't give a damn about the Shinsengumi!
(近藤)まぁまぁ そう照れるな！
(沖田)また敵ができたぜ｡
I've made another rival.
[Note: Okita now has to fight Hijikata AND Shinpachi for the vice-chief position.]
♪♪～
はぁ…｡
Impossible!
(門下生)
まさか 若様と敏木斎様が…｡
How could the Young Lord and Binbokusai-sama lose?
(輿矩)ｷｻﾏら！ 何をやっとるか!!
Damn you all!
What're you waiting for?!
あんな勝負は ﾊﾅから関係ないの！
いいから さっさと➡
That game meant nothing from the very beginning!
Forget about that and slay those scoundrels!
賊どもを成敗しちゃいなさい！
Don't let them sully our celebrity pedigree any further!
これ以上 ｾﾚﾌﾞの血を汚すな！
(敏木斎)
輿矩 もう いかげんにせい｡
Koshinori, that's enough.
ﾜｼらの負けじゃ｡
We lost.
Back down.
退け！ これは
九兵衛が 自ら約束したこと｡
Kyubei made them a promise himself.
おとなしく お妙ちゃんを返せ｡
Return Otae-chan without a fight.
Papa!
ﾊﾟﾊﾟ上！ っつうか
もとから私は 女どうしの…｡
I was against two women from the very start...
Don't say any more.
もう何も言うな｡
いや…｡
I know we told her to become a man, but...!
確かに 男になれとは言ったが…｡
(敏木斎)もう何も言うな｡
Don't say any more.
すまんのぅ… 九兵衛｡
I'm sorry, Kyubei.
じゃが これで
よかったのかもしれんのぅ｡
But this may have turned out for the best.
男だ 女だ 責めるつもりはねえよ｡
Man, woman... I'm not going to hold it against you.
だが ｱｲﾂは知ってたはずだ｡
But I think he knew...
お前が どんなつもりで
自分の左目になろうとしてたか｡
why you tried to be his left eye.
お前は知ってたはずだ｡
And you knew, too.
そんなもん背負って
ｱｲﾂのところへ行ったところで➡
Going to him while shouldering that burden wasn't going to solve anything.
何も解決できねえことくらい｡
お前らは知ってたはずだ｡
You both knew that doing something like this wasn't going to make anyone happy.
こんなことしても
誰も幸せになれねえことくらい｡
ごめんなさい…｡
I'm...sorry...
You don't have to apologize.
謝る必要なんてねえよ… 誰も｡
Nobody does.
みんな 自分の守りたいもの
守ろうとしただけだ｡
Everyone was simply trying to protect what was important to them.
That's all this was.
それだけだ｡
♪♪～
((お妙:ごめんなさい｡
Forgive me...
私… 私が
九ちゃんの左目になる！))
I...I will be your left eye, Kyu-chan.
《九兵衛:知ってたはずだ》
I should have known.
((輿矩:九兵衛… 強くなれ！
Kyubei!
To survive in this Yagyu clan, you have to become strong!
この柳生家で生き残るために！))
《知ってたはずだ…》
I should have known.
((みんな 自分の守りたいものを
守ろうとしただけだ｡
Everyone was simply trying to protect what was important to them.
それだけだ…))
That's all this was.
♪♪～
あの男の言うとおりだ｡
What that man said is right.
ﾎﾞｸは みんな知っていた｡
I knew it all along.
(九兵衛)勝手なﾏﾈして
ｷﾐに重いかせをつけ➡
My selfishness shackled you with a heavy burden.
ｷﾐの思いを知りつつも
見て見ぬﾌﾘをした｡
I knew what you were feeling, but pretended to ignore it,
ｷﾐを そばにおきたいばかりに…｡
all because I wanted you near me.
(九兵衛)それでもｷﾐは
ﾎﾞｸを守ろうとしたね｡
Yet you still tried to protect me...
ﾎﾞｸの左目になるって…｡
by saying you'd become my left eye...
(九兵衛)父上や おじいさまが➡
I also knew that Father and Grandfather were trying to protect me by raising me as a boy.
ﾎﾞｸを守らんとして
男として育てたことも知ってる｡
(九兵衛)でも どこかで恨んでた｡
But somewhere inside of me, I resented them for it.
ﾎﾞｸを 男でも女でもない
存在にしたこと…｡
They made me into someone who is neither man nor woman...
ﾎﾞｸが こうなったのは
誰のせいでもない｡
No one else is to blame for my becoming like this... It's my fault for being weak.
自分自身の弱さのせいなのに｡
(九兵衛)それでも みんな
ﾎﾞｸを最後まで守ろうとしてくれた｡
Yet everyone tried to protect me to the very end.
結局 ﾎﾞｸは守られてばかりで➡
As it turned out, everyone was protecting me-nothing had changed.
前と何も変わらない｡
約束なんて
何も果たせちゃいなかったんだ｡
I couldn't keep any of my promises.
(九兵衛)ﾎﾞｸは 弱い…｡
I'm...weak.
♪♪～
(九兵衛)妙ちゃん…｡
Tae-chan...
(九兵衛)妙ちゃん｡
Why did things turn out this way?
なんで こんなふうに
なっちゃったんだろう
いつから こんなふうに… ｸｯ…｡
When did it start...?
ﾎﾞｸも ﾎﾝﾄは みんなと一緒に➡
I wanted to play house and cat's cradle with everyone else.
ままごとや あやとりしたかった｡
みんなみたいに きれいな着物で
街を歩きたかった｡
I wanted to wear a pretty kimono and walk around town like everyone else.
妙ちゃんみたいに…➡
I wanted to become like you, Tae-chan... A strong girl with a kind heart.
強くて優しい女の子に
なりたかった｡
Kyu-chan... You are Kyu-chan.
九ちゃん…
九ちゃんは九ちゃんよ｡
(お妙)男も女も関係ない｡
It doesn't matter if you're a boy or a girl.
私の大切な親友…｡
You're my precious and dear friend.
(お妙)だから 泣かないで…｡
So...don't cry...
(泣き声)
それでも… お侍さん？
And you call yourself a...samurai...
(泣き声)
妙ちゃん…｡
Tae-chan.
(九兵衛)ごめんなさい…｡
I'm sorry... I'm so sorry...
But today, it's okay to cry.
(お妙)でも…➡
今日くらい 泣いたっていいよね？
♪♪～
(お妙)女の子だもの…｡
After all, you are a girl.
(泣き声)
Welcome!
(ﾎｽﾃｽたち)いらっしゃいませ～！
(ﾎｽﾃｽ)うわ～っ！
なに この ﾐｲﾗ男！
Who is this mummy?!
Don't come near me!
(ﾎｽﾃｽ)怖っ！
こっち来ないで！ 悪霊退散!!
Go away evil spirit!
(ﾎｽﾃｽ)いや～！
(黒服)土方さん ご指名は？
Hijikata-san, who would you like?
そうですか…
みんなは 来られないんだ…｡
I see.
They all couldn't come...
I caused so much trouble, so I wanted to make it up to them.
いろいろ 迷惑をかけたから
お詫びをと思ってたんですけど…｡
土方さんも すいませんでした｡
I'm sorry about what happened to you, too, Hijikata-san.
Because of me...you look like a mummy.
私のせいで そんな ﾐｲﾗ男に…｡
ｵﾒｴのためじゃねえ｡
I didn't do it for you.
(土方)ｵﾚは ただ ｹﾝｶしにいって
ﾐｲﾗ男に なっただけだ｡
I went to fight, and came out a mummy, that's all.
私… 最低ですよね｡
I'm...as low as it gets, aren't I?
(お妙)結局 勝手なことをして
いろんな人を 傷つけてしまった｡
As it turns out, I did a selfish thing...and hurt everyone.
I caused trouble for Kyu-chan and everyone else.
(お妙)九ちゃんも みんなにも
迷惑かけて…｡
I did those things with half-hearted feelings,
最後まで
押し通すことも できないのに➡
and wasn't even able to go through with it in the end.
半端な気持で あんなことして…｡
What I did didn't help anyone.
私がしたことは 結局
誰のためにも ならなかった…｡
(土方)釈迦じゃ あるめえし➡
You're not Buddha.
You think you can bring salvation to everyone you meet?
目の前のもん すべて
救えるとでも 思ってたのかよ？
いくら 骨 砕こうが➡
There are people you can save and others you can't save no matter how hard you try.
救えるもんも ありゃ
救えねえもんも ある｡
(土方)だから 何だ？
Is the way you live your life so fragile that you'd break just because of that?
(土方)そんなもんで折れるほど
お前さんの生き方は➡
もろいもんだったのか？
今…
お前の言う 半端な優しさでも➡
Right now,
if there was someone you could save with that half-hearted sort of kindness you just talked about...
救えるものが あるとしたら…➡
お前 どうする？
What would you do?
(司会)
皆様 お待たせいたしました｡
Thank you all for your patience.
(司会)新郎新婦 入場です！
The bride and groom will now make their entrance!
♪♪～
(拍手)
銀さん｡
Gin-san.
How do people end up in situations like this?
人間 いったい どう転ぶと
あんなことに なるんですか？
This is just one step away from a shitty marriage meeting.
見合いで 脱糞して
ﾜﾝﾄﾗｯﾌﾟ入れると ああなるんだよ｡
Boss, this isn't something to laugh about.
旦那～ 笑いごとじゃないです｡
いや 笑ってねえよ｡
つうか 笑えねえよ｡
No, I'm not laughing.
I can't.
This is the first time I've felt like crying at another man's wedding.
他人の結婚式で
泣きそうになったのは 初めてだ｡
Isn't there anything we can do?
なんとか なりませんかね～？
(沖田)この披露宴は
ただの顔見せみたいなもんでね➡
This reception is simply a formality to introduce the couple.
Later, they'll go to the Princess's planet.
このあと 王女の星で
正式な婚礼を挙げれば➡
Once the formal wedding is done, Kondo-san will become one of the gorillas.
近藤さんも
晴れて ｺﾞﾘﾗの仲間入り｡
He's not coming back.
(沖田)もう 帰ってきやせん｡
Tonight is our only chance to ruin the match.
(沖田)ぶち壊すのは
今夜しか ねえんです｡
Did you say ruin, Okita-kun?
ぶち壊すって 沖田く～ん｡
This reception's been ruined from the start.
最初から この披露宴
壊れてるだろう？
ｺﾞﾘﾗだらけだもの｡ 最初から
壊れてるもん 壊すなんて➡
There's nothing but gorillas here.
Not even I can ruin something that's been ruined from the start.
さすがのｵﾚにも できねえよ｡
ｺﾞﾘﾗだらけだもの｡
Nothing but gorillas.
そりゃあねえぜ 旦那｡
That's cruel, Boss.
After all is said and done, the Shinsengumi did play a role in rescuing Mistress.
なんやかんやで ｵﾚたち
ねえさん救うのに➡
ひと役 買ったんですぜ｡ これで
貸し借りなしに しやしょうや｡
Do this and we'll call it even.
[無線]
This is Kondo.
こちら 近藤｡
応答願います どうぞ～！
Respond, over.
What're you guys waiting for?!
お前ら なに やってんだ!?
Hurry up and ruin this reception! Over.
早く 披露宴 ぶち壊してくれ
どうぞ～!!
This is what you're good at!
[無線](近藤)お前ら
こんなの 得意だろうが！
I didn't invite you guys just for the banquet! Over.
[無線]ご馳走 食わせるために
呼んだんじゃねえんだぞ どうぞ!!
ご馳走って お前…
これ ﾊﾞﾅﾅしか ねえじゃねえか｡
What banquet? There's nothing but bananas!
あんま ｵﾚたち
ﾅﾒんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ！ どうぞ～｡
Don't treat us like fools! Over.
今回 ｵﾚたち真選組は
派手に動けん！
We Shinsengumi can't do anything violent this time.
(近藤)この結婚は
松平の とっつぁんが 動いてる！
Old man Matsudaira is behind this marriage.
あれに逆らえば
真選組は 消される！
If we go against him, the Shinsengumi will be finished!
That's why you outsiders are the only ones I can ask. Over.
外野の お前らに
頼むしかねえんだ どうぞ！
Where are these from? Over.
[無線](神楽)どこ産だ？ どうぞ！
あぁっ!?
Huh?
I'm asking where these bananas are from. Over.
このﾊﾞﾅﾅは
どこ産だと聞いているｱﾙ｡
どうぞ～！
[無線](近藤)ﾊﾞﾅﾅのことは➡
Never mind the bananas! You like those bananas, don't you?! Over.
どうでもいいんだっつうの！
ちょっと➡
気に入ってるじゃねえか ﾊﾞﾅﾅ！
どうぞ～!!
Bananas are the king of fruits. Over.
[無線](神楽)果物の王様は
やっぱり ﾊﾞﾅﾅｱﾙ｡ どうぞ～！
どうぞ！ じゃねえよ！
んなこと いちいち➡
Don't "over" me!
You don't need to report such things! Over.
報告してんじゃねえ！ どうぞ～!!
Hey, I have to pee. Where's the john?
[無線]おい ちょっと
小便してえんだけど 便所どこ？
どうぞ～！
そのへんのﾔﾂに聞け どうぞ～!!
Over.
Ask someone near you! Over.
[無線](沖田)旦那 ｵﾚが 案内しやす｡
こちらへ｡ どうぞ～｡
Boss, I'll show you. Follow me. Over.
What's the point of doing that over the transceiver?!
って！
ﾄﾗﾝｼｰﾊﾞｰで やる意味 あんのか～!!
お前らだけで 会話
成立してんだろうが どうぞ！
You're just talking amongst yourselves! Over.
《ﾀﾞﾒだ～！
ｺｲﾂら 全然 やる気ねえ～!!
I'm doomed!
They have no intention of rescuing me! Over.
どうぞ～》
Will the bride and groom please step forward?
(司会)それでは新郎新婦
どうぞ 前へ｡
(司会)皆様 たいへん長らく
お待たせいたしました｡
We have kept you all in suspense long enough.
(司会)では これより
夫婦 初めての共同作業に➡
We will now have...
the couple do their first ceremony together as husband and wife.
移らせていただきます｡
Whaaat?!
《えぇ～っ!?
ちょ… まっ… えぇ～っ!?
Just a min... Whaaa?!
ｹｰｷ入刀だろう これ 普通！
えっ!? ﾊﾞﾅﾅ入刀!?
Isn't it usually the cutting of the cake?!
Or the banana?!
No, no, no, no.
いやいや いやいや！
おかしいよ！ これ！
Something's wrong here.
確かに 共同作業だけれども…
えぇ～っ!?
It's definitely something that's done together, but not this!
Pops, what's going on?!
とっつぁん… これ…！》
《松平：近藤… これは
子孫繁栄を重んずる➡
Kondo, this is a Planet Shojo wedding tradition to show respect
猩猩星に伝わる
婚礼の伝統行事だ｡ 男を見せろ》
for the prosperity of their offspring.
Show them you're a man.
《なんだ その親指は！
やれってか？
What's with that thumbs up?!
You want me to do it?!
やれっていうのか!?
誰か あの指 折ってくれ!!
Is that what you want?!
Somebody, break that thumb!
ふざけるな！ どこぞの
ﾏﾆｱｯｸな ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵじゃねえんだよ！
You've got to be kidding!
This isn't some perverted video shoot!
加藤じゃねえんだよ…｡
I'm not Kato!
ﾀｶじゃなくて ｽｽﾞﾒなんだよ
ｵﾚみたいなもんは！
I'm not a hawk, I'm a sparrow!
[Note: Refers to male porn actor Taka Kato. Taka means "hawk" in Japanese.]
That's what I am!
Even worse, everyone's watching!
しかも 全員 ｶﾞﾝ見じゃねえか！
さっきまで
ﾊﾞﾅﾅに夢中だったくせに➡
Until a minute ago, they were enamored over their bananas,
今度は ｵﾚのﾊﾞﾅﾅかぁ？
but now they want to watch my banana?!
Shinpachi-kun, help me!
新八君 助けてくれ～!!》
I'm taking the rest home with me.
残りは 持って帰ろう｡
Forget the Tupperware!
《近藤 ﾀｯﾊﾟは いいから！
持ち帰らなくていいから ﾊﾞﾅﾅ！
You don't have to take bananas home!
どこまで 家庭的なんだ ｷﾐは!?
How domestic can you get?!
あぁぁぁ!!
…お妙さん｡
Otae-san.
最後に ｷﾐの笑顔
もう一度 見たかった》
I wanted to see your smiling face one last time.
♪♪～
ｲﾃﾃﾃ…｡
左手に ちょっとかかりました｡
どうぞ｡
I got some on my left hand. Over.
(沖田)便器から こぼれました｡
どうぞ｡
I dribbled a little outside. Over.
旦那 その後 ねえさんの様子は
どうなんです？
Boss, how has Mistress been?
あぁ？ やっぱ ちょっと
元気ねえみたいよ｡
She's been a bit down.
Women are troublesome because they're so difficult to figure out.
女は めんどくさくて
よく わからんわ｡
If things end like this, Kondo-san's efforts will have been for nothing.
これじゃ
近藤さんが報われねえや｡
ねえさんの笑顔 見るためだけに
がんばったってのに…｡
He worked so hard just to see her smile.
心配いらねえよ｡
Don't worry about it.
The thing about women is they get depressed on their own and they get over it on their own.
勝手に落ち込んで
勝手に立ち直るのが女だ｡
(沖田)そっちじゃねえですよ｡
That's not what I meant.
このまま 猿の惑星行きじゃ
報われねえっつったんですよ｡
If Kondo-san ends up going to the planet of the apes, he'll have nothing at all.
旦那 ﾎﾝﾄに
なんとかならんのですか？
Boss, isn't there anything we can do?
そっちも 心配いらねえよ
あの女…｡
You don't have to worry about it with that woman.
She'll...
♪♪～
make it up to him.
借りは返すぜ｡
…お妙さ～ん!!
Otae-saaan!
姉上!!
(みんな)姉御～!!
Sis!
Mistress!
Finally!
(山崎)ついに… ついに
局長と めおとになる決意を…！
She's finally made up her mind to be the Chief's wife!
(吠え声)
The gorillas!
(山崎)ｺﾞﾘﾗどもが！
もう 構うもんか～っ！
Oh shoot!
Let's go, guys!
(隊士)いくぞ ﾃﾒｴら！
真選組がｺﾞﾘﾗごときに➡
The Shinsengumi can't lose to the likes of gorillas!
ﾍｺﾍｺしてられっか～！
We'll decide who our Chief's bride is going to be!
ｵﾚたちの 局長の嫁は
ｵﾚたちが決める！
(隊士たち)守れ～！
局長と ねえさんの愛の道を～!!
Protect the Chief and Mistress's path to love!
《みんな…》
Guys...
Kondo!
近藤！ 惚れた女がいるなら
なぜ 言わねえ!?
Why didn't you tell me you were in love with someone?!
年寄りが
余計なことしちまったぜ｡
This old man did something he shouldn't have!
幸せになりな!!
Be happy!
《とっつぁん…｡
Pops...
みんな… みんな…｡
All you guys... Everyone...
うっ… うぅっ…｡
帰りたい… ｵﾚ…➡
I want to go back...
I...
みんなのところへ 帰りたい…！》
want to go back to everyone.
(お妙)うぉぉぉっ!!
(近藤)お妙さん！
Otae-san.
ﾃﾒｴ！ 何してくれてんだぁ!?
私の お…｡
You bastards!
What the hell are you doing with my hu...
《おっ 夫？ 男!?》
Hu-Husband?!
Her man?!
で どうなの？ 実際のところ｡
So what's the bottom line?
(沖田)ねえさんは 近藤さんのこと
どう思ってんの？
How does Mistress really feel about Kondo-san?
You guys don't understand women at all, do you?
(土方)ｵﾒｴらは ﾎﾝﾄに
女心がわかってねえな｡
惚れてる｡
いやよ いやよも好きのうちって➡
She loves him.
Playing hard to get is a sign of love.
言うだろ？
ありゃ 間違いなく惚れてる｡
She loves him, all right.
おぉ… 弟に➡
What kind of sick show were you going to expose my brother to?!
何とんでもねえもん
見せてくれとるんじゃぁぁ!!
♪♪～
ｹﾎｹﾎｯ… 姉上！
Sis!
Big Sis!
姉御！
(山崎)えっ？ ねえさん!?
Mistress!
(受付)あの… お名前だけでも｡
At least tell us your name.
(九兵衛)気持だけ 渡しにきた｡
It's merely a gesture of my goodwill.
(受付)でも
こんなにたくさん ご祝儀…｡
But this is such a large gift...
(九兵衛)いいんだ｡
いろいろ迷惑かけたし…➡
I want to do it....
I caused quite a lot of trouble...
それに… 見たかったものも
ようやく見れたしな｡
And besides...
I finally saw what I wanted to see.
♪♪～
This is where it was, after all.
(九兵衛)
やっぱり そこにあったか｡
♪♪～
[A Minute with 9th Grade Class Z Ginpachi Sensei]
A minute with...
Ginpachi Sensei!
Today, I have some news for everyone.
Onishi-kun, who studied with us for a year-and-a-half
here at GinTama High School, is transferring to the prestigious One Piece High School.
He insists that it was because of his father's job
and not because the academic standards are higher at the other school.
It's unfortunate, after we all got to know each other.
But remember you will all still be friends even if you're separated.
So, Onishi, stand out in hallway one last time.
[The next episode...]
Subject: Poopy.
I'm in deep poop!
Deep, deep poopy!
Real deep.
How deep? I'm talking deep.
What the hell is this?!
The next episode... "You Say Kawaii so Often, You Must Really Think You're Cute Stuff."
[And in the episode after that, the Odd Jobs becomes warriors?! "You Don't Stand in Line for the Ramen, You Stand in Line for the Self Satisfaction."]
[(Administrative Notice) We have sad news to report. Please wait until further notice.]
えぇ… 今日は みんなに
伝えなくてはならないことがある｡
１年半 一緒に勉強してきた
ｵｵﾆｼ君が この銀魂高校から➡
名門 ﾜﾝﾋﾟｰｽ学園に
転校することになった｡
お父さんの仕事の関係で
決して 向こうの高校のほうが➡
偏差値高そう とか
そういうことではないそうだ｡
せっかく仲よくなれたのに
残念だが 離れてしまっても➡
みんなは ずっと友達だからな｡
というわけで ｵｵﾆｼ…｡
最後に もう１回
廊下に立ってなさい｡